<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE cc SYSTEM "cc.dtd">
<cc version="CC:2022" revision="0.9">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <a-class name="Security Target (ST) evaluation" id="ase">
    <ac-introduction>
      <para>
        Evaluating an ST is required to demonstrate that the ST is sound and internally
        consistent, and, if the ST is based on a PP-Configuration, or one or more PPs or packages,
        that the ST is a correct instantiation of the PP-Configuration, PPs, and packages. These
        properties are necessary for the ST to be suitable for use as the basis for a TOE
        evaluation.
      </para>
      <para>
        Clause 9 should be used in conjunction with CC Part 1, Annexes B, C and D as these annexes
        clarify the concepts here and provide many examples.
      </para>
    </ac-introduction>
    <ma-introduction>
      <para>
        This clause describes the evaluation of an ST. The ST evaluation should be started prior
        to any TOE evaluation sub-activities since the ST provides the basis and context to
        perform these sub-activities. The evaluation methodology in this subclause is based on the
        requirements on the ST as specified in CC Part 3 class <xref id="ase"/>.
      </para>
      <para>
        This clause should be used in conjunction with CC Part 1, Annexes A, B and C, as these
        Annexes clarify the concepts here and provide many examples.
      </para>
    </ma-introduction>
    <ma-application-notes>
      <subclause id="re-using-in-ase" title="Re-using the evaluation results of certified PPs">
        <para>
          While evaluating an ST that is based on one or more certified PPs, it may be possible to
          re-use the fact that these PPs were certified. The potential for re-use of the result of a
          certified PP is greater if the ST does not add threats, OSPs, assumptions, security
          objectives and/or security requirements to those of the PP. If the ST contains much more
          than the certified PP, re-use may not be useful at all.
        </para>
        <para>
          The evaluator is allowed to re-use the PP evaluation results by doing certain analyses
          only partially or not at all if these analyses or parts thereof were already done as part
          of the PP evaluation. While doing this, the evaluator should assume that the analyses in
          the PP were performed correctly.
        </para>
        <para>
          An example would be where the PP contains a set of security requirements, and these were
          determined to be internally consistent during the PP evaluation. If the ST uses the exact
          same requirements, the consistency analysis does not have to be repeated during the ST
          evaluation. If the ST adds one or more requirements, or performs operations on these
          requirements, the analysis will have to be repeated. However, it may be possible to save
          work in this consistency analysis by using the fact that the original requirements are
          internally consistent. If the original requirements are internally consistent, the
          evaluator only has to determine that:
          <list>
            <item>
              the set of all new and/or changed requirements is internally consistent, and;
            </item>
            <item>
              the set of all new and/or changed requirements is consistent with the original
              requirements.
            </item>
          </list>
        </para>
        <para>
          The evaluator notes in the ETR each case where analyses are not done or only partially
          done for this reason.
        </para>
        <para>
          The same re-use discussion applies to an ST claiming conformance to a certified
          PP-Configuration.
        </para>
      </subclause>
      <subclause id="composition-in-ase" title="Composition">
        <para>
          The composite-specific work units defined in <xref id="ase_comp"/> are intended to be
          integrated as refinements to the evaluation activities of the <xref id="ase"/> class
          listed in the following table. The other activities of the <xref id="ase"/> class do not
          require composite-specific work units.
        </para>
        <table>
          <title>
            <xref id="ase_comp"/>
          </title>
          <tgroup cols="4">
            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  Assurance family
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  Evaluation activity
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  Evaluation work unit
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  Composite-specific work unit
                </entry>
              </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_obj"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_obj.2.1e"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_obj.2-1"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_comp.1-5"/>
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry/>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_obj.2.1e"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_obj.2-1"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_comp.1-6"/>
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry/>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_obj.2.1e"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_obj.2-3"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_comp.1-6"/>
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.1.1e"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.1-16"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_comp.1-1"/>
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry/>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.2.1e"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.2-13"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_comp.1-1"/>
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry/>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.1.1e"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.1-16"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_comp.1-2"/>
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry/>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.2.1e"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.2-13"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_comp.1-2"/>
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry/>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.2.1e"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.2-12"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_comp.1-3"/>
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry/>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.2.1e"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_req.2-4"/>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <xref id="ase_comp.1-4"/>
                </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
      </subclause>
    </ma-application-notes>
    
    
    
    <a-family name="ST introduction" id="ase_int">
      <af-objectives>
        <para>
          The objective of this family is to describe the TOE in a narrative way on three levels of
          abstraction: TOE reference, TOE overview and TOE description.
        </para>
        <para>
          Evaluation of the ST introduction is required to demonstrate that the ST and the TOE are
          correctly identified, that the TOE is correctly described at three levels of abstraction
          and that these three descriptions are consistent with each other.
        </para>
      </af-objectives>
      <a-component name="ST introduction" id="ase_int.1">
        <msa-objectives>
          <para>
            The objective of this sub-activity is to determine whether the ST and the TOE are
            correctly identified, whether the TOE is correctly described in a narrative way at three
            levels of abstraction (TOE reference, TOE overview and TOE description), and whether these
            three descriptions are consistent with each other.
          </para>
        </msa-objectives>
        <msa-input>
          <para>
            <list>
              <item>
                the ST.
              </item>
            </list>
          </para>
        </msa-input>
        <ae-developer id="ase_int.1.1d">
          The developer shall provide an ST introduction.
        </ae-developer>
        <ae-content id="ase_int.1.1c">
          The ST introduction shall contain an ST reference, a TOE reference, a TOE overview and a
          TOE description.
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ase_int.1.2c">
          The ST reference shall uniquely identify the ST.
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ase_int.1.3c">
          The TOE reference shall uniquely identify the TOE.
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ase_int.1.4c">
          The TOE overview shall summarize the usage and major security features of the TOE.
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ase_int.1.5c">
          The TOE overview shall identify the TOE type.
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ase_int.1.6c">
          The TOE overview shall identify any non-TOE hardware/software/firmware required by the
          TOE.
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ase_int.1.7c">
          For a multi-assurance ST, the TOE overview shall describe the TSF organization in terms of
          the sub-TSFs defined in the PP-Configuration the ST claims conformance to.
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ase_int.1.8c">
          The TOE description shall describe the physical scope of the TOE.
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ase_int.1.9c">
          The TOE description shall describe the logical scope of the TOE.
        </ae-content>
        <ae-evaluator id="ase_int.1.1e">
          The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets all requirements for
          content and presentation of evidence.
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-1">
            <ae-dc-element id="ase_int.1.1c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall check that the ST introduction contains an ST reference, a TOE
              reference, a TOE overview and a TOE description.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-2">
            <ae-dc-element id="ase_int.1.2c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall examine the ST reference to determine that it uniquely identifies the
              ST.
            </para>
            <para>
              The evaluator determines that the ST reference identifies the ST itself, so that it may be
              easily distinguished from other STs, and that it also uniquely identifies each version of
              the ST, e.g. by including a version number and/or a date of publication.
            </para>
            <para>
              In evaluations where a CM system is provided, the evaluator may validate the uniqueness of
              the reference by checking the configuration list. In the other cases, the ST should have
              some referencing system that is capable of supporting unique references (e.g. use of
              numbers, letters or dates).
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-3">
            <ae-dc-element id="ase_int.1.3c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall examine the TOE reference to determine that it uniquely identifies the
              TOE.
            </para>
            <para>
              The evaluator determines that the TOE reference uniquely identifies the TOE, so that it is
              clear to which TOE the ST refers, and that it also identifies the version of the TOE, e.g.
              by including a version/release/build number, or a date of release.
            </para>
            <para>
              In the end of the evaluation, the evaluator shall check the TOE reference, and any unique
              identifiers associated with the TOE physical components are consistent with the
              identifier(s) assigned to the TOE evaluated in work units related to <xref id="alc_cmc"/>.x.1C and the configuration list evaluated in work units related to <xref id="alc_cms"/>.x.2C.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-4">
            <para>
              The evaluator shall examine the TOE reference to determine that it is not misleading.
            </para>
            <para>
              If the TOE is related to one or more well-known products, it is allowed to reflect this in
              the TOE reference. However, this should not be used to mislead consumers and it must be
              made clear which part of the product has been evaluated.
            </para>
            <para>
              When a TOE needs some required non-TOE hardware/software/firmware to run properly, the TOE
              reference may include the name of the non-TOE hardware/software/firmware used by the TOE,
              however it must be made clear that the non-TOE hardware/software/firmware has not been
              evaluated.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-5">
            <ae-dc-element id="ase_int.1.4c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall examine the TOE overview to determine that it describes the usage and
              major security features of the TOE.
            </para>
            <para>
              The TOE overview may describe security features that are provided by the product, and/or
              those that users may expect in that product type, but it must clearly distinguish those
              features that are evaluated and those that are not evaluated.
            </para>
            <para>
              The TOE overview shall be consistent with information provided in other sections of the
              Security Target such as the TOE description, the security objectives, the security
              functional requirements, and the TOE summary specification. In addition to ensuring the
              evaluated security features are consistently described throughout the ST, this means that
              any security feature that is not evaluated is only discussed within the ST introduction,
              or else is explicitly identified as not evaluated in each other place where it is
              mentioned (failure to make this identification means that this work unit is assigned a
              fail verdict).
            </para>
            <para>
              The TOE overview in an ST for a composed TOE should describe the usage and major security
              feature of the composed TOE, rather than those of the individual component TOEs.
            </para>
            <para>
              The evaluator determines that the overview is clear enough for consumers, and sufficient
              to give them a general understanding of the intended usage and major security features of
              the TOE.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-6">
            <ae-dc-element id="ase_int.1.5c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall check that the TOE overview identifies the TOE type.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-7">
            <para>
              The evaluator shall examine the TOE overview to determine that the TOE type is not
              misleading.
            </para>
            <para>
              There are situations where the general consumer would expect certain functionality of the
              TOE because of its TOE type. If this functionality is absent in the TOE, the evaluator
              determines that the TOE overview adequately discusses this absence.
            </para>
            <para>
              There are also TOEs where the general consumer would expect that the TOE should be able to
              operate in a certain operational environment because of its TOE type. If the TOE is unable
              to operate in such an operational environment, the evaluator determines that the TOE
              overview adequately discusses this.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-8">
            <ae-dc-element id="ase_int.1.6c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall examine the TOE overview to determine that it identifies any non-TOE
              hardware/software/firmware required by the TOE.
            </para>
            <para>
              While some TOEs are able to run stand-alone, other TOEs (notably software TOEs) need
              additional hardware, software or firmware to operate. If the TOE does not require any
              hardware, software or firmware, this work unit is not applicable and therefore considered
              to be satisfied.
            </para>
            <para>
              The evaluator determines that the TOE overview identifies any additional hardware,
              software and firmware needed by the TOE to operate. This identification does not have to
              be exhaustive, but detailed enough for potential consumers of the TOE to determine whether
              their current hardware, software and firmware support use of the TOE, and, if this is not
              the case, which additional hardware, software and/or firmware is needed.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-9">
            <ae-dc-element id="ase_int.1.7c"/>
            <para>
              For a multi-assurance ST, the evaluator shall examine the TOE overview to determine that
              it describes the TSF organization in terms of the sub-TSFs defined in the PP-Configuration
              to which the ST claims conformance. The TSF organization is possibly completed with
              details of the actual TOE.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-10">
            <ae-dc-element id="ase_int.1.8c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall examine the TOE description to determine that it describes the
              physical scope of the TOE.
            </para>
            <para>
              The evaluator determines that the TOE description lists the hardware, firmware, software
              and guidance parts that constitute the TOE and describes them at a level of detail that is
              sufficient to give the reader a general understanding of those parts.
            </para>
            <para>
              As a minimum, the TOE description will cover the following elements:
              <list>
                <item>
                  each separately delivered part of the TOE, which will be identified by its unique
                  identifier and the current format (binary, wafer, inlay, pdf, docx, chm, etc.);
                </item>
                <item>
                  the delivery method used by the developer to make available each part to the TOE consumer
                  (web site download, courier delivery, etc.).
                </item>
              </list>
            </para>
            <para>
              The physical description will also include some clear statements about the evaluated TOE
              configuration. In the case where a product can have multiple physical components, and
              therefore multiple configurations, the evaluated configurations must be briefly described
              and identified.
            </para>
            <para>
              The evaluator also determines that there is no possible misunderstanding as to whether any
              hardware, firmware, software or guidance part is part of the TOE or not.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-11">
            <ae-dc-element id="ase_int.1.9c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall examine the TOE description to determine that it describes the logical
              scope of the TOE.
            </para>
            <para>
              The evaluator determines that the TOE description discusses the logical security features
              offered by the TOE at a level of detail that is sufficient to give the reader a general
              understanding of those features.
            </para>
            <para>
              The evaluator also determines that there is no possible misunderstanding as to whether any
              logical security feature is offered by the TOE or not.
            </para>
            <para>
              An ST for a composed TOE may refer out to the description of the logical scope of the
              component TOEs, provided in the component TOE STs to provide the majority of this
              description for the composed TOE. However, the evaluator determines that the composed TOE
              ST clearly discusses which features of the individual components are not within the
              composed TOE, and therefore not a feature of the composed TOE.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
        </ae-evaluator>
        <ae-evaluator id="ase_int.1.2e">
          The evaluator shall confirm that the TOE reference, the TOE overview, and the TOE
          description are consistent with each other.
          <m-workunit id="ase_int.1-12">
            <para>
              The evaluator shall examine the TOE reference, TOE overview and TOE description to
              determine that they are consistent with each other.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
        </ae-evaluator>
      </a-component>
    </a-family>
    
    
    
    
  </a-class>
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <f-class name="Privacy" id="fpr">
    <fc-introduction>
      <para>
        This class contains privacy requirements. These requirements provide a user protection
        against discovery and misuse of identity by other users.
      </para>
    </fc-introduction>
    <fc-informative-notes>
      <para>
        This class describes the requirements that can be levied to satisfy the users' privacy
        needs, while still allowing the system flexibility as far as possible to maintain
        sufficient control over the operation of the system.
      </para>
      <para>
        In the components of this class there is flexibility as to whether or not authorized users
        are covered by the required security functionality.
      </para>
      <para type="example">
        A PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST author can consider it appropriate not to
        require protection of the privacy of users against a suitably authorized user.
      </para>
      <para>
        This class, together with other classes (such as those concerned with audit, access
        control, trusted path, and non-repudiation) provides the flexibility to specify the
        desired privacy behaviour. On the other hand, the requirements in this class can impose
        limitations on the use of the components of other classes, such as <xref id="fia"/> or
        <xref id="fau"/>.
      </para>
      <para type="example">
        If authorized users are not allowed to see the user identity (perhaps because of Anonymity
        or Pseudonymity), it will obviously not be possible to hold individual users accountable
        for any security relevant actions they perform that are covered by the privacy
        requirements. However, it can still be possible to include audit requirements in a PP,
        PP-Module, functional package or ST, where the fact that a particular security relevant
        event has occurred is more important than knowing who was responsible for it.
      </para>
      <para>
        Additional information is provided in the application notes for class <xref id="fau"/>,
        where it is explained that the definition of "identity" in the context of auditing can
        also be an alias or other information that can identify a user.
      </para>
      <para>
        This class describes four families: Anonymity, Pseudonymity, Unlinkability and
        Unobservability. Anonymity, Pseudonymity and Unlinkability have a complex
        interrelationship. When choosing a family, the choice should depend on the threats
        identified. For some types of privacy threats, pseudonymity will be more appropriate than
        anonymity.
      </para>
      <para type="example">
        If there is a requirement for auditing.
      </para>
      <para type="example">
        In addition, some types of privacy threats are best countered by a combination of
        components from several families.
      </para>
      <para>
        All families assume that a user does not explicitly perform an action that discloses the
        user's own identity.
      </para>
      <para type="example">
        The TSF is not expected to screen the user name in electronic messages or databases.
      </para>
      <para>
        All families in this class have components thatscoped through operations. These operations
        allow the author of a PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST to state the cooperating
        users/subjects to which the TSF must be resistant.
      </para>
      <para type="example">
        An instantiation of anonymity can be, "The TSF ensure that the users and/or subjects are
        unable to determine the user identity bound to the teleconsulting application".
      </para>
      <para>
        It is noted that the TSF should not only provide this protection against individual users,
        but also against users cooperating to obtain the information.
      </para>
      <para type="note">
        The reader's attention is drawn to ISO/IEC TS 19608, which is based on CC. ISO/IEC TS
        19608:
        <list type="itemized">
          <item>
            selecting and specifying SFRs from CC Part 2 to protect Personally Identifiable
            Information (PII);
          </item>
          <item>
            the procedure to define both privacy and SFRs in a coordinated manner;
          </item>
          <item>
            developing privacy functional requirements as extended components based on the privacy
            principles defined in ISO/IEC 29100 through the paradigm described in CC Part 2.
          </item>
        </list>
      </para>
    </fc-informative-notes>
    <f-family name="Anonymity" id="fpr_ano">
      <ff-behaviour>
        <para>
          This family ensures that a user can use a resource or service without disclosing the
          user's identity. The requirements for anonymity provide protection of the user identity.
          Anonymity is not intended to protect the subject identity.
        </para>
      </ff-behaviour>
      <ff-application-notes>
        <para>
          Anonymity ensures that a subject may use a resource or service without disclosing its user
          identity.
        </para>
        <para>
          The intention of this family is to specify that a user or subject can take action without
          releasing its user identity to others such as users, subjects, or objects. The family
          provides the author of a PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST with a means to identify
          the set of users that cannot see the identity of someone performing certain actions.
        </para>
        <para>
          Therefore. if a subject, using anonymity, performs an action, another subject will not be
          able to determine either the identity or even a reference to the identity of the user
          employing the subject. The focus of the anonymity is on the protection of the user's
          identity, not on the protection of the subject identity; hence, the identity of the
          subject is not protected from disclosure.
        </para>
        <para>
          Although the identity of the subject is not released to other subjects or users, the TSF
          is not explicitly prohibited from obtaining the users identity. In case the TSF is not
          allowed to know the identity of the user, <xref id="fpr_ano.2"/> can be invoked. In that
          case, the TSF should not request the user information.
        </para>
        <para>
          The interpretation of "determine" should be taken in the broadest sense of the word.
        </para>
        <para>
          The Components leveling and description distinguishes between the users and an authorized
          user. An authorized user is often excluded from the component, and therefore allowed to
          retrieve a user's identity. However, there is no specific requirement that an authorized
          user be able to have the capability to determine the user's identity. For ultimate
          privacy, the components would be used to say that no user or authorized user can see the
          identity of anyone performing any action.
        </para>
        <para>
          Although some systems will provide anonymity for all services that are provided, other
          systems provide anonymity for certain subjects/operations. To provide this flexibility, an
          operation is included where the scope of the requirement is defined. If the author of a
          PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST wants to address all subjects/operations, the
          words "all subjects and all operations" can be provided.
        </para>
        <para>
          Possible applications include the ability to make enquiries of a confidential nature to
          public databases, respond to electronic polls, or make anonymous payments or donations.
        </para>
        <para type="example">
          Potential hostile users or subjects include providers, system operators, communication
          partners and users, who smuggle malicious parts (including malware) into systems. All of
          these users can investigate usage patterns (such as which users used which services) and
          misuse this information.
        </para>
      </ff-application-notes>
      <f-component name="Anonymity" id="fpr_ano.1">
        <fco-rationale>
          <para>
            This component ensures that the identity of a user is protected from disclosure. There may
            be instances, however, that a given authorized user can determine who performed certain
            actions. This component gives the flexibility to capture either a limited or total privacy
            policy.
          </para>
        </fco-rationale>
        <fco-levelling>
          <para>
            <xref id="fpr_ano.1"/> requires that other users or subjects are unable to determine the
            identity of a user bound to a subject or operation.
          </para>
        </fco-levelling>
        <fco-audit level="minimal">
          The invocation of the anonymity mechanism
        </fco-audit>
        <f-element id="fpr_ano.1.1">
          The TSF shall ensure that
          <assignment>
            <assignmentitem>
              set of users and/or subjects
            </assignmentitem>
            <assignmentnotes>
              <para>
                the author of a PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST should specify the set of users
                and/or subjects against which the TSF provides protection. For example, even if the author
                of a PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST specifies a single user or subject role, the
                TSF must not only provide protection against each individual user or subject but also
                protect with respect to cooperating users and/or subjects.
              </para>
            </assignmentnotes>
          </assignment>
          are unable to determine the real user name bound to
          <assignment>
            <assignmentitem>
              list of subjects and/or operations and/or objects
            </assignmentitem>
          </assignment>
          .
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
      <f-component name="Anonymity without soliciting information" id="fpr_ano.2">
        <fco-hierarchical fcomponent="fpr_ano.1"/>
        <fco-rationale>
          <para>
            This component is used to ensure that the TSF is not allowed to know the identity of the
            user.
          </para>
        </fco-rationale>
        <fco-levelling>
          <para>
            <xref id="fpr_ano.2"/> enhances the requirements of <xref id="fpr_ano.1"/> by ensuring
            that the TSF does not ask for the user identity.
          </para>
        </fco-levelling>
        <fco-audit equal="fpr_ano.1"/>
        <f-element id="fpr_ano.2.1">
          The TSF shall ensure that
          <assignment>
            <assignmentitem>
              set of users and/or subjects
            </assignmentitem>
            <assignmentnotes>
              <para>
                the author of a PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST should specify the set of users
                and/or subjects against which the TSF provides protection.
              </para>
            </assignmentnotes>
          </assignment>
          are unable to determine the real user name bound to
          <assignment>
            <assignmentitem>
              list of subjects and/or operations and/or objects
            </assignmentitem>
          </assignment>
          .
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="fpr_ano.2.2">
          The TSF shall provide
          <assignment>
            <assignmentitem>
              list of services
            </assignmentitem>
            <assignmentnotes>
              <para>
                the author of a PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST should identify the list of
                services which are subject to the anonymity requirement, for example, "the accessing of
                job descriptions".
              </para>
            </assignmentnotes>
          </assignment>
          to
          <assignment>
            <assignmentitem>
              list of subjects
            </assignmentitem>
            <assignmentnotes>
              <para>
                the author of a PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST should identify the list of
                subjects from which the real user name of the subject should be protected when the
                specified services are provided.
              </para>
            </assignmentnotes>
          </assignment>
          without soliciting any reference to the real user name.
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
    </f-family>
  </f-class>
</cc>