<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE cc SYSTEM "cc.dtd">
<cc version="CC:2022" revision="0.9">
  <a-class name="Protection Profile Configuration evaluation" id="ace">
    <ac-introduction>
      <para>
        Evaluating a PP-Configuration
      </para>
      <para>
        The class <xref id="ace"/> is defined for <xref id="ape"/>. The class <xref id="ace"/> defines the requirements
        for:
        <list type="itemized">
          <item>
            Evaluating the PP (components <xref id="ace_int.1"/>, <xref id="ace_ccl.1"/>, <xref id="ace_spd.1"/>, <xref id="ace_obj.1"/>
            or <xref id="ace_obj.2"/>, <xref id="ace_req.1"/> or <xref id="ace_req.2"/>, and <xref id="ace_mco.1"/>).
          </item>
          <item>
            Evaluating (see <xref id="ace_cco.1"/>).
          </item>
        </list>
      </para>
    </ac-introduction>
    <ma-introduction>
      <para>
        The process 
      </para>
      <para>
        <xref id="ace"/> does PPs:
        PP<sub>1</sub>, … PP<sub>n</sub>, PP-Modules: M<sub>1</sub>, … M<sub>k</sub>,
        where n ≥ 2 or k ≥ 1. <xref id="fig/a_c_e-pp-modules-pp-configuration.png"/> following steps:
        <list>
          <item>
            evaluation <xref id="ape"/> requirements);
          </item>
          <item>
            if
          </item>
          <item>
            evaluate <xref id="ace_mco.1"/>;
          </item>
          <item>
            evaluate  <xref id="ace_cco.1"/>.
          </item>
        </list>
      </para>
      <para>
        Due 
      </para>
      <figure entity="fig/a_c_e-pp-modules-pp-configuration.png" title="Relationship between PPs and PP-Modules in a PP-Configuration" id="fig/a_c_e-pp-modules-pp-configuration.png"/>
      <para>
        The <xref id="ace"/> based on <xref id="ape"/>'s.
      </para>
    </ma-introduction>
    <a-family name="PP-Module conformance claims" id="ace_ccl">
      <af-objectives>
        <para>
          The
        </para>
      </af-objectives>
      <a-component name="PP-Module conformance claims" id="ace_ccl.1">
        <aco-dependencies>
          <aco-dependsoncomponent acomponent="ace_int.1"/>
          <aco-dependsoncomponent acomponent="ace_ecd.1"/>
          <aco-or>
            <aco-dependsoncomponent acomponent="ace_req.1"/>
            <aco-dependsoncomponent acomponent="ace_req.2"/>
          </aco-or>
        </aco-dependencies>
        <msa-objectives>
          <para>
            The 
          </para>
        </msa-objectives>
        <msa-input>
          <para>
            <list>
              <item>
                the PP-Module;
              </item>
              <item>
                the SFR and SAR package(s) that the PP-Module claims conformance to;
              </item>
              <item>
                the PP-Configuration.
              </item>
            </list>
          </para>
        </msa-input>
        <ae-developer id="ace_ccl.1.1d">
          The
        </ae-developer>
        <ae-developer id="ace_ccl.1.2d">
          The.
        </ae-developer>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.1c">
          The.
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.2c">
          The".
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.3c">
          The
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.4c">
          The
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.5c">
          The
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.6c">
          The 
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.7c">
          The
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.8c">
          The 
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.9c">
          The
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.10c">
          For
        </ae-content>
        <ae-content id="ace_ccl.1.11c">
          The
        </ae-content>
        <ae-evaluator id="ace_ccl.1.1e">
          The
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-1">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.1c"/>
            <para>
              The 
            </para>
            <para>
              The
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-2">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.2c"/>
            <para>
              The
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-3">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.3c"/>
            <para>
              The
            </para>
            <para>
              If
            </para>
            <para>
              If
            </para>
            <para>
              If
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-4">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.4c"/>
            <para>
              The
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-5">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.5c"/>
            <para>
              The
            </para>
            <para>
              If the CC conformance claim contains CC Part 2 and/or CC Part 3 conformant, the evaluator
              determines that the extended components definition does not define functional/assurance
              components.
            </para>
            <para>
              If the CC conformance claim contains CC Part 2 and/or CC Part 3 extended, the evaluator
              determines that the extended components definition defines at least one extended
              functional/assurance component.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-6">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.6c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall check, for each identified functional package, that the package
              definition is complete.
            </para>
            <para>
              If the PP-Module does not claim conformance to a functional package, this work unit is not
              applicable and therefore considered to be satisfied.
            </para>
            <para>
              For all functional packages that are not claimed by a component in the PP-Module's base,
              the evaluator determines that the package definition is conformant to the requirements
              from CC Part 1, Clause 9 "Packages" by checking that the functional package includes:
              <list>
                <item>
                  A functional package identification, giving a unique name, version, date, sponsor, and the
                  CC edition;
                </item>
                <item>
                  A functional package overview, giving a narrative description of the security
                  functionality;
                </item>
                <item>
                  A component rationale that provides the rationale for selecting the functional
                  components/requirements included in the package;
                </item>
                <item>
                  If the package defines an SPD then:
                  <list type="itemized">
                    <item>
                      the package includes a security requirements rationale;
                    </item>
                    <item>
                      the package includes a security objectives rationale if security objectives for the
                      environment are defined;
                    </item>
                    <item>
                      if the package is a direct rationale package, there are no security objectives for the TOE
                      defined and the security requirements rationale maps directly to the SPD;
                    </item>
                    <item>
                      If the package is not a direct rationale package, then security objectives for the TOE are
                      defined, the security objectives rationale covers the objectives with respect to the SPD,
                      and the security requirements rationale maps the requirements to the security objectives.
                    </item>
                  </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                  one or more security components or requirements (the functional package SFRs);
                </item>
                <item>
                  If extended components have been specified then the functional package includes an
                  extended components definition.
                </item>
              </list>
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-7">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.7c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall check that, for each identified package, the conformance claim states
              a claim of either package-conformant, package-augmented or package-tailored.
            </para>
            <para>
              The evaluator determines that for all functional packages claimed by the PP-Module that
              are already claimed by one of the PPs or PP-Modules in its PP-Module Base(s), the
              PP-Module augments or tailors the functional package as it is instantiated in its
              PP-Module Base (in this case the PP-Module would claim the functional package as "Package
              Augmented" or "Package Tailored" (as appropriate)). Otherwise, the evaluator confirms that
              functional packages claimed by a PP-Module Base component are not claimed by the
              PP-Module.
            </para>
            <para>
              If the PP-Module does not claim conformance to a package, this work unit is not applicable
              and therefore considered to be satisfied.
            </para>
            <para>
              If the functional package conformance claim contains package-conformant, the evaluator
              determines that all assumptions, threats, OSPs, security objectives and SFRs included in
              the package are included in identical form by the PP-Module (including via its PP-Module
              Base).
            </para>
            <para>
              If the functional package conformance claim contains package-augmented, the evaluator
              determines that all assumptions, threats, OSPs, security objectives and SFRs included in
              the package are included in identical form by the PP-Module except that the PP-Module
              shall include additional selection items values for an at least one of the SFRs with
              existing selections in the package, and may also have one or more SFRs that are
              hierarchically higher than an SFR in the functional package.
            </para>
            <para>
              If the functional package conformance claim contains package-tailored, the evaluator
              determines that all assumptions, threats, OSPs, security objectives and SFRs included in
              the package are included in identical form by the PP-Module except that the PP-Module
              shall include additional selection values for at least one of the SFRs in the package, and
              may also have one or more SFRs that are hierarchically higher than an SFR in the
              functional package.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-8">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.8c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall check, for each identified assurance package, that the package
              definition is complete. If the PP-Module does not claim conformance to an assurance
              package, this work unit is not applicable and therefore considered to be satisfied. If the
              assurance package is a reference to one of the assurance packages contained in CC Part 5
              then this work unit is also considered to be satisfied. The evaluator determines that the
              package definition is conformant to the requirements from CC Part 1, Clause 9 "Packages"
              by checking that the assurance package includes:
              <list>
                <item>
                  An assurance package identification, giving a unique name, version, date, sponsor, and the
                  CC edition;
                </item>
                <item>
                  An assurance package overview, giving a narrative description of the security
                  functionality;
                </item>
                <item>
                  One or more security components or requirements (the assurance package SARs) drawn from CC
                  Part 3, extended assurance components or some combination of both;
                </item>
                <item>
                  An assurance package shall not include an SPD or security objectives;
                </item>
                <item>
                  If extended components have been specified then the assurance package includes an extended
                  components definition.
                </item>
              </list>
            </para>
            <para>
              A security requirements rationale that provides the rationale for selecting the assurance
              components/requirements included in the package.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-9">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.9c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall check that, for each identified assurance package, the conformance
              claim states a claim of either package-conformant or package-augmented.
            </para>
            <para>
              If the PP-Module does not claim conformance to an assurance package, this work unit is not
              applicable and therefore considered to be satisfied.
            </para>
            <para>
              If the assurance package conformance claim contains package-conformant, the evaluator
              determines that all constituent parts included in the assurance package are included in
              identical form by the PP-Module, without modification.
            </para>
            <para>
              If the assurance package conformance claim contains package-augmented, the evaluator
              determines that all constituent parts of the assurance package included in the PP-Module
              are identical to those given in the assurance package except that the PP-Module shall
              contain at least one additional SAR or one SAR that is hierarchically higher than those
              contained in the assurance package.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-10">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.10c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall check the conformance statement of the PP-Module to determine that it
              contains an allowed-with statement that lists the set of other PPs and PP-Modules that can
              be specified in the components statement of a PP-Configuration that includes the
              PP-Module.
            </para>
            <para>
              The evaluator confirms that the listed PPs and PP-Modules are not part of any of the
              PP-Module Base sets.
            </para>
            <para>
              There is no further check other than existence of the list for the PP-Module's
              allowed-with statement.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-11">
            <para>
              The evaluator shall check that, for each PP-Module Base for the PP-Module, all components
              in the PP-Module Base identify all other components of the PP-Module Base in their
              allow-with statements.
            </para>
            <para>
              This is an iterative operation, and it is important to note that the rule about a
              PP-Module not including any components in its PP-Module Base in its allowed-with statement
              holds for any PP-Module in the PP-Module Base.
            </para>
            <para>
              All PPs in a given PP-Module Base set will have to allow-with all other components (PPs
              and PP-Modules) in that PP-Module Base set.
            </para>
            <para>
              PPs and PP-Modules in one PP-Module Base set do not, however, have to express an allowed
              with relationship with components in any other PP-Module Base set, since two PP-Module
              Base sets will not simultaneously be specified in a PP-Configuration
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
          <m-workunit id="ace_ccl.1-12">
            <ae-dc-element id="ace_ccl.1.11c"/>
            <para>
              The evaluator shall check the conformance statement of the PP-Module under evaluation to
              confirm that:
              <list>
                <item>
                  if any derived Evaluation Methods and Evaluation Activities are required by other items
                  used with the PP-Module (e.g. a base PP), or required by other items to which the
                  PP-Module claims conformance (e.g. packages), then these are all identified in the
                  PP-Module under evaluation, along with any derived Evaluation Methods and Evaluation
                  Activities that the PP-Module itself requires;
                </item>
                <item>
                  the list of derived Evaluation Methods and Evaluation Activities is sufficiently
                  structured and detailed to unambiguously identify and locate every member of the list;
                </item>
                <item>
                  if there is any overlap in the scope of the identified Evaluation Methods and Evaluation
                  Activities (i.e. where an overlay exists as described in CC Part 4) then the rationale for
                  the resulting set of Evaluation Methods and Evaluation Activities is applicable to the TOE
                  as described by the PP-Module under evaluation.
                </item>
              </list>
            </para>
            <para>
              The intention of this work unit is to ensure that when evaluating a TOE that claims
              conformance with the PP-Configuration that contains the PP-Module under evaluation then
              the correct Evaluation Methods and Evaluation Activities can be used. This means that
              identification in the PP-Module need not list individual Evaluation Activities where these
              are unambiguously included in a listed Evaluation Method. Similarly, where multiple
              Evaluation Methods or Evaluation Activities are included in a single document then it is
              sufficient to reference the document, provided this does lead to unambiguous
              identification of the Evaluation Methods and Evaluation Activities that apply to the
              PP-Module under evaluation.
            </para>
            <para type="example">
              If a document lists multiple different Evaluation Methods applicable to different use
              cases then it would not be sufficient to reference the document: the relevant use cases
              would also have to be identified.
            </para>
          </m-workunit>
        </ae-evaluator>
      </a-component>
    </a-family>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </a-class>

  <f-class name="Trusted path/channels" id="ftp">
    <fc-introduction>
      <para>
        have the following general characteristics:
        <list type="itemized">
          <item>
            the
          </item>
          <item>
            use
          </item>
          <item>
            the
          </item>
        </list>
      </para>
      <para>
        In this
      </para>
      <para>
        A
      </para>
      <para>
        Families 
      </para>
    </fc-introduction>
    <fc-informative-notes>
      <para>
        Users
      </para>
      <para>
        Absence of a trusted path
      </para>
    </fc-informative-notes>
    <f-family name="Inter-TSF trusted channel" id="ftp_itc">
      <ff-behaviour>
        <para>
          This
        </para>
      </ff-behaviour>
      <ff-application-notes>
        <para>
          This family
        </para>
        <para type="example">
          An example
        </para>
      </ff-application-notes>
      <f-component name="Inter-TSF trusted channel" id="ftp_itc.1">
        <fco-rationale>
          <para>
            This
          </para>
        </fco-rationale>
        <fco-levelling>
          <para>
            <xref id="ftp_itc.1"/> requires
          </para>
        </fco-levelling>
        <fco-management>
          Configuring
        </fco-management>
        <fco-audit level="minimal">
          Failure
        </fco-audit>
        <fco-audit level="minimal">
          Identification 
        </fco-audit>
        <fco-audit level="basic">
          All
        </fco-audit>
        <fco-audit level="basic">
          Identification
        </fco-audit>
        <f-element id="ftp_itc.1.1">
          The T
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="ftp_itc.1.2">
          The TSF shall permit
          <selection exclusive="NO">
            <selectionitem>
              the TSF
            </selectionitem>
            <selectionitem>
              another trusted IT product
            </selectionitem>
            <selectionnotes>
              <para>
                the 
              </para>
            </selectionnotes>
          </selection>
          to
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="ftp_itc.1.3">
          The
          <assignment>
            <assignmentitem>
              list
            </assignmentitem>
            <assignmentnotes>
              <para>
                the
              </para>
            </assignmentnotes>
          </assignment>
          .
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
    </f-family>
    
    
  </f-class>
</cc>